弟兒小時候很搗蛋
Dale was a mischievous child and very vain
- 很愛漂亮
他，每一個大的孩子他也跟人家玩
He got along with everyone,
小的孩子也跟他
older and younger kids alike
非常非常的活潑
He was very outgoing and vivacious
他要開舞會
One time he wanted to host a dance party
那個時候，台灣
Taiwan was a very regimented society then
學生開舞會還要申請
Students needed to apply with the local police
媽媽跟他跑警察局
so Mom went with him to the police station
申請，還要找地方
and found a venue for the party
找舞會的場所
where they could dance
呂台明從小就是很乖
Tai was a very sweet child
而且是很懶
and particularly lazy
因為他
He really liked to be held, by everyone
每個小孩，你抱他
抱著他時候他就會很高興
Nothing made him happier than to be held
可是你把他抱久的時候
But if you held him for a long time,
他就不高興了
he would become irritated
那你把他放下來
Then if you put him down
放下來放在椅子上，或放在床上
on a chair or in a bed
他馬上就笑了
He would immediately smile
他就不舒服了
He didn't like to be uncomfortable
他就要舒服
Comfort was very important to him
而且，從小的時候就怕死
He also had a tremendous fear of death
每天要叫爸爸給他找那個
Everyday he would ask Dad to find him
長生不老藥
the elixir that would guarantee eternal life
要吃長生不老藥
He needed the elixir
結果，逼得爸爸没辦法
In the end Dad came up with a plan
從香港回來時候就弄一個維他命丸給他吃
and brought home vitamins from Hong Kong
吃了之後他就不怕死了
The placebo effect worked like a charm
以前他很怕死
And then he was no longer afraid of dying
說妳從小
Anchi was a very healthy baby
生下來的時候
She never got sick, she was our little "Iron Girl"
身體很好
身體好，是小鐵人
但是脾氣壞得不得了
But oh my did she have a temper
那我就說
when I made her formula
「馬上給你沖啊，馬上來了！」I
would have to say, it's coming
- 「快了！快了！」 the bottle is coming
-
一直叫一直叫
想再吃就生氣了
otherwise she would get very angry
假設
假設沖了比較慢的話，你就生氣
Suppose we were a little late with
就不吃了
getting the bottle to her, she would then refuse to drink it
安琪才三歲
When Anchi was just three
把姑媽氣了個半死
she was already a force to be reckoned with
那個梁媽媽給你取了個名字叫
One of our friends called her
戳心子
"the one who pierced hearts"
專門戳人家心
She was adept at hitting your pain spot
為什麼我會這麼直的個性呢？Why
was I like this?
對啊
Yeah
不知道為什麼
we have no idea!
像誰呢？Who
do I resemble?
不知道，可能是像你奶奶吧
I don't know, maybe your paternal grandmother?
像奶奶，可能像奶奶
Yes, I think like your grandma
奶奶的脾氣也很壞
Your grandma also had quite a temper
我的
My seven grandchildren
七個孫子
最大的叫「Alan」The
eldest is Alan
這個孩子
Alan is very pragmatic
他是很現實的
他每天說我要多賺錢
Everyday he told me he wanted to make a lot of money
中間他就
He changed jobs and studied for his Masters
辭掉了工作
in Financial Engineering at UCLA
去讀碩士
就修經濟這行
所以他現在畢業了
Now he has graduated and works at a bank (PIMCO)
找到了銀行的工作
他從小
He was raised by his maternal grandmother Popo
是由婆婆養大他的
Popo adored him
那個婆婆非常愛他
They spent a lot of time together
因為在一起生活的時間很久
and he is always very kind to her
他對婆婆很好
老二
Our second grandson is Evan
叫「Evan」
他呢
Evan is a very honest boy
原來很老實的
不多講話
He is not chatty and is rather introverted
是很內向的
大學畢業以後讀碩士
After he graduated from college he pursed his
碩士完了繼續讀博士
Masters and then a PhD degree
他最後的目的就是
I think his goal is to become a college professor
做一個大學教授
老三
Our third grandson is Ryan
叫「Ryan」
他比較外向
Ryan is an extrovert
功課還不錯
He is a good student but he doesn't apply himself
可是他不用功讀書
as well as he can
哩哩拉拉的
It took him a while and he finally graduated
終於大學畢業了
可是他
But instead of looking for a stable job he swung between
没有好好去找工作
一會兒要去台灣教英文
teaching English in Taiwan or in China
一會兒也想去大陸教英文
我看他
The way I see it is that he's not focused on teaching English
不是教英文
他
教課没教很久
但是他女朋友就是一大堆
but more on meeting girls
弟兒哥有一個女兒
Dale has one daughter
叫琳琳
and her name is Irene
她有一點害羞
She's on the shy and quiet side
不太喜歡講話
元元的三個小孩
Tai has 3 children
大的是濱濱
The eldest is Nicholas
濱濱非常乖
Nicholas is a very sweet child
從小就媽媽帶大的
Nainai brought him up so he is very close to her
所以他跟媽媽的感情
兩個人的感情都好得不得了
They love each other very much
濱濱不太愛講話
Nicholas is not a chatterbox
很愛讀書
He is dedicated to his studies and is an excellent student
所以他的功課非常好
老二
Tai's second son is Alex
叫濤濤
他性格比較活潑
Alex is quite outgoing and also does well in school
功課也不錯
可是他比較愛玩
功課雖然没有哥哥好但是
Even though his grades aren't as good as his brother's
也是不錯，也是讀特別班
He is also in the gifted program
最小的一個是女兒
The youngest is Melanie
她非常的活潑
Melanie is very lively
功課也不錯
and she is also a good student
她的腦筋非常地靈活
She has a very creative mind
她對於人際關係 and she is a people person
非常好
她懂得怎麼樣騙人，怎麼樣哄人
She knows how to butter you up
關於人際關係，她會察顏觀色
and she is good at reading people
她會騙你，讓你很舒服
She tells little white lies to make you feel good
我們家 We have a very happy family
可以說是很幸福
這些都是媽媽的功勞
and this is all possible because of Mom
媽媽從小帶你們
Mom took care of all of you tirelessly
教育你們
taught you what's important
愛你們
and loved you unconditionally
可是很辛苦 She has put in a lot of effort
你們長大了
Now you're all grown and she's old
可是她卻老了
但是她心裡還是很安慰
but she is content and comforted
我們雖然老了，可是我們心裡
While we have aged we are very happy
還是非常的愉快
看你們每一個人
We are proud of your accomplishments
都有成就
每一個孫子，書也讀得好
Every grandchild is a good student
身體也非常好
healthy and vivacious
也活潑
我跟媽媽心裡
For Mom and me, our hearts are filled with joy
都非常地高興